Guide to the Building Trades Oral History Project OH.045
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Building Trades Oral History Project
1998-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
OH.045
3.5 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Unless otherwise noted, materails are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Interviews conducted by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives staff between 1998 and 2001. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.094 and 1978.015.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
- Transcripts, cuid14499 (Box 1)
- Allen, Kenneth (Metalic Lathers Union, Local 46), Dec 27, 2001; cuid14452; 453468 (Box 5, Cassette 28)
- Alongi, Vincent (Carpenters and Joiners, Local 2090), Oct 24, 2000; cuid14453; 453469 (Box 5, Cassette 34A)
- Andrucki, George (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 28), Dec 2, 1998; cuid14454; 453470 (Box 5, Cassette 33A, Cassette 33B)
- Bartels, Robert (Steamfitters Local 638), Dec 18, 2001; cuid14455; 453471 (Box 5, Cassette 32A)
- Blain, William (International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3), Apr 15, 1998; cuid14456; 453472 (Box 5, Cassette 31A, Cassette 31B)
- Bombardiere, Mio (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), Nov 18, 1999; cuid14457; 453473 (Box 5, Cassette 30A, Cassette 30B)
- Brennan, Vincent (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 21, 1998; cuid14458; 453474 (Box 5, Cassette 27A)
- Colbert, Neil (Tile, Marble and Terrazo, Local 7), Jun 10, 1999; cuid14459; 453475 (Box 2)
- Coletti, Louis J. (Building Trades Employers Association), Jul 31, 2001; cuid14460; 453476 (Box 2, Cassette 29A, Cassette 29B)
- Collins, Paul (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), Oct 4, 1999; cuid14461; 453477 (Box 2, Cassette 26A, Cassette 26B)
- Contello, Sal (Bricklayers, Local 1), Jun 12, 1998; cuid14462; 453478 (Box 2, Cassette 25A)
- Cush, Edward (Ironworkers, Local 361), Mar 21, 2001; cuid14463; 453479; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 2, Cassette 24A, 24B, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14463A, cuid14463B)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 67 min. [B]
- Daly, Martin (Carpenters District Council), Oct 29, 1998; cuid14464; 453480 (Box 2, Cassette 23A)
- Doyle, Jack (Ironworkers, Local 40), Jan 15, 2002; cuid14465; 453481; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and Part 2 of the same interview. (Box 2, Cassette 6A, 6B, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14465A, cuid14465B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Durations: 94 min. [A] and 40 min. [B]
- Forde, Michael (Carpenters District Council), Mar 20, 2002; cuid14466; 453482 (Box 2, Cassette 22A)
- Gerosa, Al (Cement League of Greater New York), Oct 1, 2001; cuid14467; 453483 (Box 2, Cassette 21A, Cassette 21B)
- Glynn, Eugene (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 22, 1998; cuid14468; 453484 (Box 2, Cassette 19A, Cassette 19B)
- Hill, Charlie (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), May 11, 1999; cuid14469; 453485 (Box 2, Cassette 20A, Cassette 20B)
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), May 7, 2001; cuid14470; 453486 (Box 2, Cassette 17A, Cassette 17B)
- Holloway, Dennis (International Masonry Institute of Bricklayers and Allied Trades), Jun 25, 1998; cuid14471; 453487 (Box 2, Cassette 16A)
- Humphrey, Thomas (Stone Derrickmen and Riggers, Local 197), Oct 12, 1999; cuid14472; 453488 (Box 2, Cassette 15A)
- Kelly, John (Iron Workers, Local 40), Nov 14, 2001; cuid14473; 453489; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 3, Cassette 12A, 12B, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14473A, cuid14473B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassettes, Duration: 57 min. [A] and 87 min. [B]
- Kelly, William (Iron Workers, Local 197), Nov 12, 1999; cuid14474; 453490 (Box 3, Cassette 11A, Cassette 11B)
- Kennedy, John (Building and Construction Trades Council of Nassau and Suffolk Counties), Oct 31, 2001; cuid14475; 453491 (Box 3, Cassette 10A, Cassette 10B)
- Lanzafame, Santo (Bricklayers, Local 1), Nov 18, 1998; cuid14476; 453492 (Box 6, Cassette 39A)
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), Mar 19, 2001; cuid14477; 453493 (Box 3, Cassette 8A, Cassette 8B)
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), Dec 28, 2001; cuid14478; 453494 (Box 3, Cassette 9A, Cassette 9B, Cassette 9C)
- Levine, Louis (Former Deputy Commissioner of Labor), Jan 20, 1999; cuid14479; 453495 (Box 3, Cassette 7A, Cassette 7B)
- Lusardi, Dennis (Ironworkers, Local 580), Dec 28, 2001; cuid14480; 453496; 1 audiocassette (Box 3, Cassette 46A, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14480)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 92 min.
- Maiello, Gene (New York District of Carpenters), Nov 27, 2000; cuid14481; 453497 (Box 3, Cassette 13A, Cassette 13B)
- Malloy, Edward (Building and Construction Trades Council), Aug 8, 2002; cuid14482; 453498 (Box 2, Cassette 4A)
- Martin, Raymond (General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen), Jul 31, 2002; cuid14483; 453499 (Box 2, Cassette 2A, Cassette 2B)
- McGuire, Ray (Contractors Association of Greater New York), Nov 12, 2001; cuid14484; 453500 (Box 6, Cassette 38A, Cassette 38B)
- Nicastri, Ronald (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), Jun 21, 1999; cuid14485; 453501 (Box 6, Cassette 37A, Cassette 37B)
- O'Brien, William (Painters District Council 9), Nov 13, 2001; cuid14486; 453502 (Box 5, Cassette 36A, Cassette 36B)
- O'Donnell, John (Association of Plumbing Contractors), Oct 26, 2001; cuid14487; 453503 (Box 3, Cassette 14A, Cassette 14B)
- O'Kane, Richard (Ironworkers, Local 361), Mar 9, 2001; cuid14488; 453504; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 6, Cassette 45A, 45B, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14488A, cuid14488B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A], 9 min [B]. Note: Volume fluctuates between interviewer and interviewee.
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), Nov 20, 2000; cuid14489; 453505 (Box 6, Cassette 44A, Cassette 44B)
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), Oct 19, 2000; cuid14490; 453506 (Box 6, Cassette 43A, Cassette 43B)
- Simmons, Alan (Ironworkers District Council), Jan 19, 2001; cuid14491; 453507; 1 audiocassette (Box 6, Cassette 42A, 42B, E-records tamwag_oh45, Cassette cuid14491)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. Only Tape 42A has been digitzed.
- Thomassen, Peter (Dockbuilders, Local 1456), Nov 30, 1998; cuid14492; 453508 (Box 3, Cassette 41A)
- Torpey, John R. (Steamfitters, Local 638), Jan 12, 1999; cuid14493; 453509 (Box 3, Cassette 40A, Cassette 40B)
- Ulrich, Werner (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 6, 1998; cuid14494; 453510 (Box 4, Cassette 48A, Cassette 48B)
- Valegatos, Sandy (Painters District Council 9), Jan 10, 2001; cuid14495; 453515 (Box 4, Cassette 47A, Cassette 47B)
- Walsh, Edward J. (Ironworkers, Local 40), Jan 5, 2001; cuid14496; 453516; 3 audiocassette Parts 1, 2, and 3 of the same interview (Box 4, Cassette 49A, 49B, 49C, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14496A, cuid14496B, cuid14496C)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Durations: 63 min. [A], 63 min. [B], 10 min. [C]
- Walsh, Robert (Ironworkers, Local 40), Aug 24, 2001; cuid14497; 453517; 2 audiocassette Duplicates. One tape is the master, and the other is a high speed dub. (Box 4, Cassette 50A, E-records tamwag_oh45, E-records cuid14497)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 116 min.
- Winbush, Zacharius (Bricklayers, Local 1), Jun 12, 1998; cuid14498; 453518 (Box 4, Cassette 451A)
- Vagelatos-Winbush, cassettes 47A-51A, Preservation Masters and copies, cuid14500
- Adam, Eleanor, Jun 01, 2000; cuid14537 (Box 2, Cassette 5A, Cassette 5B)
- Bloom, April, Jul 11, 2000; cuid14538 (Box 2, Cassette 1A, Cassette 1B)
- Robinson, Guy, Aug 09, 2002; cuid14539 (Box 2, Cassette 3A, Cassette 3B)
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), Jun 07, 2001; cuid14540 (Box 2, Cassette 18B)
- Access Audio CDs (Box Access Audio 2)